Welcome back to a push in under 3
minutes. No time for intros. Let's get
into it. So, the guilded age. When I see
this era of American history, what I
think of is governmental corruption, big
business, and disgustingly rich people
having power over the government. All
that stuff we will get to in our next
topic. But for this topic, what we need
to talk about is the sheer amount of
industrialization that happened during
the Gilded Age. You might remember the
market revolution. In the early 1800s,
you had people making machines. During
the guilded age, you now have machines
making machines. In the past, industry
relied on iron. Now with the Bessemer
process, steel is what takes over. In
the market revolution, factories ran on
steam. Now everything runs on
electricity and it transforms
production. And the other part of this
is now with all this new railroad
expansion, the US has access to so much
land. And that land is a literal gold
mine of resources such as coal, iron,
oil, timber, copper, etc. But anyway,
you see what's happening here. We have
so many resources and a lot of new
innovations. This will make large-scale
businesses. These businesses will become
extremely popular. The people owning
these businesses will get really rich.
The US will stand down and adopt a lair
capitalist economic policy. And there
you go. That's the guilded age coming to
life. On the screen now are AP style
questions for this topic. Pause now.
I'll put the answers on the screen now.
I will see you in the next one.